這是本仇恨的書 用來報復每個外強中乾的
It's a book of hate, to wreak revenge on every pompous
爬上卡特韋夫人門檻的小爬蟲
trembling worm who taps at Mrs Castaway's door!
你是...?      蘇糖就是我的姓名
And you are? Sugar is all there is to my name.
你的人生從今以後就不同了
Your life is going to be very different from now on.
我想讓你搬到切普斯托路去
I would like you to move to Chepstow Villas.
和你住在一起?
To live in your house?
做索菲的家庭教師
And become Sophie's governess.
十九年前      母親
19 years... Mother...
我們開始相依為命
.. since we embarked on this life together.
你的生活越來越神祕了 我眞好奇
Your life is becoming quite shrouded in mystery. I am so curious.
那位女士是誰 索菲?
Who is that lady, Sophie?
艾格尼絲 你幹什麼了?
Agnes, what have you done?
求你 我準備好了 救我走
Please, I'm ready. Get me away!
你是我唯一希望了
You're my only hope!
我還是你的小女孩嗎?
Am I still your little girl?
對 當然是
Yes, of course you are.
我不是瘋女人
I am not a madwoman!
艾格尼絲還是得送走
Agnes is to be put away.
可是威廉...
But, William...
再沒有人能傷害你了      時候到了?
No-one is going to hurt you any more. Is it time?
洛斯特威西爾 (康沃爾郡 英國西南)
Lostwithiel.
-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
紅玫瑰白玫瑰 第四集
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：tpring LOVEKEICO
校對：tpring
時間軸：tpring
正體中文轉製及校對：Uriel
(本片含有部分粗口)
This programme contains some strong language.
(可能引起部分觀衆不安的場面)
scenes which some viewers may find disturbing.
(以及性場面)
scenes of a sexual nature.
我得報告警...警...
I have to t tell the p... p...
太激動了對你不好
It's worse when you excite yourself.
...警察
.. the police!
我得報告警察
I have to tell the police.
艾格尼絲可能急需營救
Agnes may be in need of urgent rescue!
當然 威廉 可...
Of course, William, but...
這不是簡單的生死問題
It's not a simple question of being dead or alive.
她的處境可能生不如死
There is a fate worse than death.
可能就在此刻 一個卡特韋太太那樣的老錢婆
As we speak, some foul hag, such as your Mrs Castaway, could be
正在把她往妓院裏送
installing her in some bawdy house!
艾格尼絲那麼虛弱 應該沒人會那樣利用她的
I'm quite sure Agnes is too frail to be made use of in that way.
你沒讀過「狂歡指南」嗎?
Haven't you read More Sprees?
病入膏肓的女子也是一門生意呢
There's a nice little trade going in dying girls.
還是你忘光了?
Or perhaps you'd forgotten?
她老跟你嘮叨的這個「健康修院」
Where was this "Convent of Health"
怎麼回事?
that she blathered onto you about?
我覺得 那不是現實存在的地方
Well, I'm not sure it was a place that had a physical reality.
你知道她失蹤過吧?
You know she disappeared before?
蘇糖小姐找到她的 一半腳趾都被雪凍掉了
Miss Sugar found her with half her toes sliced off in the snow.
蘇糖小姐?      女家庭教師
Miss Sugar? The governess.
她不是我們改造的女人吧?
She's not a rescue girl, is she?
天啊 説哪裏話 當然不是
Oh, for heaven's sake! Of course not.
艾米麗 你太沈迷這個了
Emmeline, you're becoming fixated on that subject!
「讓我想想 早晨就覺得」(愛麗絲夢遊仙境)
Let me think. I always think I can remember feeling...
「有點不對頭」
a little different.
「可如果我不是自己 接着就該問」
But if I am not the same, the next question is,
「我能是誰呢?」
who in the world am I?
「唉 眞是個謎呀」
That's the great puzzle.
很高興你喜歡你的聖誕禮物書 索菲
I'm so glad you're enjoying your Christmas book, Sophie.
小姐 我媽媽還在逃跑嗎?
Miss, has my mama still run away?
對
Yes.
對 她還在逃跑      到歷史了嗎?
Yes, she has. Is it history now?
你説什麼?      歷史 亨利八世?
I beg your pardon? History? Henry VIII?
不 我記得先是地理
Er, no, geography first, I think.
給我畫幾個澳大利亞的動物好不好?
Why don't you draw me some animals from Australia?
你和艾格尼絲親近嗎?
Were you and Agnes close?
親近?
Close?
我們基本不認識
We barely knew each other.
她告訴克拉拉 在雪地裏找到她的
She told Clara the person who f... f... found her in the snow
是她唯一的朋友
was her only friend in the world.
她當時神志不清
She was very disturbed.
我只是送她回房而已
I merely escorted her back to the house.
她根本不認識你
She didn't know you at all,
可是卻信任你?
yet she trusted you?
她也沒理由不信啊
Well, she had no reason not to.
小姐      嗯?
Miss. U-hum?
亨利八世這麼想要兒子
If Henry VllI wanted a son so badly,
為什麼不娶個有兒子的女士呢?
why didn't he marry a lady who already had one?
因為要做王儲
Because to be the king's true heir
必須是國王的血脈
you need to be of the king's blood.
孩子是血做的嗎?
Are babies made of blood?
不是
No.
孩子從這裏長出來
Babies are grown in here.
怎麼長出來?
How?
嗯 如果我有個丈夫
Well, if I had a husband,
他會在我身體裏播種
he would plant a seed in me
我就會懷上孩子
and I would have a baby.
那我是從媽媽體内來的?
I came out of Mama, then?
絳紅的花瓣睡了 (A·丁尼生 1847)
Now sleeps the crimson petal
雪白的同眠去
Now the white
御道邊絲柏不再婆娑搖擺
Nor waves the cypress in the palace walk
花崗岩池中不再波光粼粼
Nor winks the gold fin in the porphyry font
螢火蟲醒來 喚醒了我和你
The firefly wakens Waken thou with me
乳白的孔雀收屏如鬼魅
Now droops the milk-white peacock like a ghost
魅影在我眼前明明滅滅
And like a ghost she glimmers unto me
大地如達納厄 灑滿星光
Now lies the Earth All Danae to the stars
你便與我心心相印
And all thy heart lies open unto me.
流星無聲掠過 只留下
Now slides the silent meteor on And leaves
一條金線 如我對你的思念
a shining furrow as thy thoughts in me.
哦 萊蒂
Oh, Letty!
抱歉 我看書看睡着了
Sorry, I fell asleep, reading.
幾點了      沒事 還很早 不過
What time is it? No, it's early, only.
拉克曼先生在找你
Mr Rackham was looking for you.
他被叫走了
He's been fetched away.
這種環境裏 要辨認很困難 先生
Identification will be difficult in these circumstances, sir.
請多注意那些沒腐爛的部分
Try and focus on the parts that are least corrupted.
提醒您一句 別看眼睛
A word of warning, don't look for the eyes.
都被鰻魚吃掉了      好的
Eels have them. All right.
是她
It is she.
是我妻子
It is my wife.
你肯定嗎 先生?
Are you sure, sir?
我肯定
I'm sure.
把她蓋起來
Cover her up!
小心 小心
Steady, steady.
好了 先生
All right, sir.
「親愛的威廉 等待結婚的日子
'Dearest William, it is so tedious to wait
眞讓我度日如年」
even this short time to be man and wife.
「我多想走出去 聽人們説
'How I long to go out and hear people say,
這是拉克曼夫婦」
"There go the Rackhams.
「他剛出版了新書
'"He has just published another book and
她剛從巴黎回來 買了三十條裙子」
she is lately returned from Paris with 30 new dresses!"'
我們的肉體終會歸於塵土
Ashes and dust are our only material remains.
和精神遺産相比 肉體不値一提
Compared to our spiritual remains, they mean nothing.
拉克曼夫人的殘軀...
Mrs Rackham's corporeal form...
您眞是個非常 非常勇敢的人
You are a brave, brave, brave man.
我聽説索菲找到家庭教師了
I heard Sophie had a new governess.
難怪她這麼開心呢
I wonder to see her so happy!
這是你第一個學生嗎 小姐...
Is she your first pupil, Miss..?
蘇糖      艾米麗·福克斯太太
Sugar. Mrs Emmeline Fox.
不 我還帶過一個小男孩
No, I looked after a little boy before.
克里斯托弗
Christopher.
在諾丁山?
In Notting Hill?
我在倫敦很多地方都住過
I've lived many different places in London.
我也去過很多地方
And I have visited many in the course of my work
開展救濟社工作
with The Rescue Society.
救濟社?
The Rescue Society?
不瞞您説 我從沒聽過
I confess, I've never heard of it.
哦 蘇糖小姐
Oh, Miss Sugar,
我的同事聽到將會多麼受傷啊
how mortified my colleagues would be to hear you say that.
恕我失陪 福克斯太太
If you will excuse me, Mrs Fox,
我今天應該看着索菲的      當然
I do think I should keep a close eye on Sophie today. Of course.
一起走走吧
Let's walk together.
我們社團的宗旨是改造妓女
We are an organisation committed to reforming prostitutes.
刻不容緩 每天都有婦女因
The urgency is great. Women die or disappear
生病 謀殺或自殺而死去 失蹤
every day through disease, murder, suicide.
昨天我剛去過一間妓院
Just yesterday, I visited a house,
老鴇叫卡特韋太太
a place known as Mrs Castaway's,
去找我在一本可恥的讀物上看到的女孩
looking for a girl I'd read about in a vile publication.
找到什麼了?
What did you find there?
那女孩早就不在了
The girl was long gone.
誰也不知她的去向
No one could say where.
卡特韋太太本人也死了
And Mrs Castaway herself had died.
死了?      新老鴇這麼説的
Died? So the new madam said,
然後給我吃了閉門羹
before she slammed the door in my face.
抱歉 蘇糖小姐
Forgive me, Miss Sugar.
哦 你喜歡你當初的老鴇
Oh, you were fond of your old madam.
是我太自大 沒考慮到這點 我眞傻
In my arrogance, I failed to imagine that. What an imbecile I am.
你想要什麼?
What do you want?
我想要證實你是誰
I wanted to verify who you were.
我是誰?
Who am I?
一個找到方向 並且不辱使命的女人
A young woman who has found her calling and means to excel at it.
有需要隨時找我
If I can ever be of service.
克里斯托弗?
Christopher?
你走錯了吧
I think you've mistaken your way.
我在找這裏原來開門的小男孩
I was looking for the little boy who used to answer the door.
要找小男孩的 叫他去找塔伯特夫人
If it's little boys he's after, send him to Mrs Talbot's.
不是男人 親愛的 是救濟社來的女士
It's not a man, dear, it's a lady from the Rescue Society.
我叫蘇糖
My name is Sugar.
我原來在這工作
I used to work here.
蘇糖?
Sugar?
不會吧...
I would never have...
快進來 親愛的 進來
Oh, well come in, dear, come in.
前幾天還有人找你呢
Someone was asking for you only a couple of days ago.
你多傳奇呀
Your fame endures!
大變樣了對吧?
Quite a change, isn't it?
我能和艾米説句話嗎?
May I have a word with Amy?
原來拉大提琴的姑娘
The girl who used to play the cello.
唉 艾米覺得我們這裏
Alas, Amy felt our house had
太專業 讓她屈才了
become too specialised for her talents.
帶那男孩走了 去哪我不記得了
Took the boy with her. Quite where escapes me.
這麼多新窯子 誰記得住啊
So many new houses, one can hardly keep up.
艾米走了 我也可以説不再上工了
With Amy gone and me no longer on what you call the factory floor
我們又少兩個姑娘
we're two girls down.
我是來打聽我...
I came to ask about my...
打聽卡特韋太太的
About Mrs Castaway.
哦 她死了 親愛的
Oh, she passed, dear.
怎麼了 她怎麼死的?
But how? How did she die?
睡過去就沒醒 親愛的
In her sleep, dear.
她給我留什麼了嗎?
Did she leave anything for me?
一封信 一句話?
A letter, a message?
發現她死了之後呢
And what happened to her after she was found,
屍體呢?
her remains?
管喪事的擡走了 對吧 親愛的?
Undertakers took her away. Isn't that right, dear?
哦 沒問題 魯克斯 布魯克斯 類似的名字
Oh, I believe so. Rookes, Brookes, something like that. Aww.
再路過這裏 記得回來玩哦
Well, do call in again, dear, if you're passing.
見到你眞好
A charm to see you.
你整個人都變了
You do look different.
我的生活全變了      是嗎?
My life is very different now. Is it?
你長胖了 不是嗎?      眞的
You've filled out so! Ain't she? Indeed.
其實我還想問 有什麼要告訴我們的嗎?
In fact, I wonder, is there something we should know?
蘇糖小姐 拉克曼先生問您回來沒有
Miss Sugar, Mr Rackham was asking if you were back.
你會縫紉嗎?
Can you sew?
縫紉?      對 你會把艾格尼絲的裙子
Sew? Yes, could you alter a dress of Agnes's so that it'd
改成你的嗎?
fit you?
呃 這我不會
Er, no I, I don't think so.
就算我會裁縫 艾格尼絲和我
Erm, even if I were a seamstress, Agnes and I were
體型完全不同
very different shapes.
眞可惜 我還打算明天下午
Shame. I'd arranged for us all to go on
全家一起出去的
a little outing together tomorrow afternoon.
全家?      你 我和索菲 去照相館
Us all? You, me and Sophie. To the photographer's studio.
照全家福
A family portrait.
早安 先生
Good day, Sir.
托維先生
Mr Tovey.
夫人 這邊請
Madam. This way.
索菲
Sophie.
這裙子一定是縮水了
This dress must have shrunk.
我現在要從天空召喚大象
I shall now summon an elephant from the sky
讓它站在我鼻尖上
and balance it on the tip of my nose.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
太棒了
Marvellous.
你好 索菲      爸爸?
Hello, Sophie. Papa?
我給你帶了禮物
I have something for you.
你覺得怎樣?      威廉?
Well, what do you think? William?
眞是個驚喜
What a pleasant surprise.
蘇糖小姐 看      哦 索菲
Miss Sugar, see here. Oh, Sophie.
像眞的一樣       眞棒 索菲
I look real! It's wonderful, Sophie!
大團圓照呢?
And what of the group portrait?
我們一起照的那張?
The one of all of us together?
可惜不太成功      唉 天啊
It wasn't a success, I'm afraid. Oh, dear.
不然改天再去試試?
Perhaps we can try again another day?
好的 索菲 改天再試
Yes, Sophie. Perhaps we will.
當然 這很冒險 機器剛發明出來
It is a risk, of course. The engineering is in its infancy.
還照老辦法吧
Leave things as they are.
你的投資要回本
To recoup your investment
需要十年好收成
you'd need ten years' excellent harvests
並且你的競爭對手不能擴張
and no expansion from your competitors.
唉...
Oh, it's...
下個世紀屬於梨牌和亞德利
The next century belongs to Pears and Yardley.
我從骨子裏堅信
I can feel it in my bones.
而且我沒有繼承人...
And without an heir to succeed me...
眼下還沒有
Without an heir so far.
你正當盛年 威廉
You are a man in his prime, William.
還記得我們第一次見面嗎?
Do you remember when we first met?
我告訴你我會為你做任何事
I told you I would do anything for you.
我們該上床了      我正這麼想呢
We should be in bed. My thoughts exactly.
不
No...
説眞的 看都幾點了
.. seriously. Look at the time.
你這個傻姑娘
You stupid, stupid girl.
你好 先生 你在找我嗎?
Hello, sir. Are you looking for me?
蘇糖?
Sugar?
是... 是你?
Is that... Is that you?
我聽説卡太太的事了
I had heard about Mrs C.
她幾時過世的? 你知道嗎?
When did she die? Do you know?
有一陣了
A while ago.
她什麼都沒留給你 連封信也沒有?
She didn't leave you nothing? A letter, even?
眞遺憾
I'm sorry.
我愛過我母親
I loved my mother.
能用用你的痰盂嗎?      儘管用
Can I use your pot? Help yourself.
哦 謝謝 還挺乾淨呢
Oh, thank you. It's even clean!
你不介意吧?
Would you mind?
我有時還點支蠟燭祭奠媽媽呢
Light a candle for her sometimes, my mum.
當然不在教堂裏
Not in church!
就是這裏      能不能幫我把包裏的手絹拿來?
Just in here. Can you pass me a handkerchief from my bag?
你去買東西了? 薄荷油和啤酒酵母
You been shopping? Pennyroyal and brewer's yeast.
給一個女僕的
One of the maids.
她試過鋅和硼砂?
She tried zinc and borax?
毫無用處
To no avail.
我最討厭這個 撕心裂肺的灼痛
I hate that the worst. Hurts like hell, the burnin'.
可憐的姑娘
Poor girl.
對 很痛
Yes, it does.
這是什麼
What's this?
替我也點支蠟燭
Light a candle for me.
「那我是誰呀?」(愛麗絲漫遊仙境)
'Who am I, then?
「先得告訴我 如果變成我喜歡的人」
'Tell me that first, and then, if I like being that person,'
「我就上來」
I'll come up.
「不然 我就待在這裏 除非再變成什麼人」
'If not, I'll stay down here till I'm somebody else.
抱歉 索菲
Oh, excuse me, Sophie.
我出去一會兒
I just need to go outside for a moment.
拉克曼先生
Mr Rackham!
簡妮
Janey!
跟我來
Follow me.
威廉 眞對不起
Oh, William. I'm so sorry.
是科魯醫生
That will be Dr Curlew.
為我而來?      在床上別動
For me? Do not move from this bed.
這房子已受夠生病的女人了
We've had quite enough sick women in this house.
我希望你好好的
I want you well.
人們從椅子上跌下 都會摔斷脖子
People break necks falling off a chair.
你從樓梯上跌下
You have fallen down a staircase
卻只扭傷了腳踝
and only have a badly sprained ankle
留下一些瘀傷
and a number of bruises to show for it.
你現在可能還沒發現瘀傷 但很快會察覺到的
You may not be aware of those bruises as yet, but you will be.
儘量躺在床上休養
Keep to your bed as much as possible.
我還有工作
I have duties to perform.
你的情況 最好...
It would be much better, in your condition...
科魯醫生
Dr Curlew,
我是這家人僱來的
I am employed in this house.
進來
Enter.
病人如何了?
How is the patient?
狀態好極了 蘇糖小姐體質很好
Remarkably well. Miss Sugar is extremely robust.
你好 索菲 過來幫我拿拿書
Hello, Sophie. Here, take these books from me.
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for heaven's sake!
你對我的狀況不好奇嗎?
Aren't you the least bit curious what happened to me?
萊蒂説你從很高的地方跌下來
Letty said that you fell down a long, long way
我不能盯着看
and I mustn't stare.
我很快會好起來
I'll be better very soon.
你爸爸現在越來越...
And now that your father...
自信能自己處理信函了
.. feels well enough to do his own correspondence,
我們有更多的時間呆在一起了
you and I can spend more time together.
我想咱們到紐西蘭了
And I think we are in New Zealand.
「親愛的拉克...」 拉克
"Dear Rackers... " Rackers.
「發生這種事我深表哀悼
"Deepest condolences aside,
但你總沒死吧」
anyone would think it was you who were dead.
「這本新書是我們最棒的一本」
"The new book is our best yet. "
「藝術之於勞動人民」
Art As Understood By The Working Man.
比別的都沒爭議吧!
Less contentious than usual!
你別不相信!
Don't you believe it!
看看這些粗活工人們
Look at that whole variety of rude working folk.
掃煙囱的人 賣魚工
Chimney sweeps, fish-sellers,
幫廚女工 小販們之類
kitchen-maids, costermongers, so forth.
給他們看看名畫的雕版
And show them engravings of famous paintings.
問問他們的意見!
Then ask them their opinion!
威廉 告訴我們你想對康絲緹斯做什麼
So, William, do tell us what you intend to do about Constance.
康絲緹斯?     我們想知道
Constance? We're dying to hear.
親愛的布利德樓夫人?
Our dear Lady Bridgelow.
她怎麼了?      你不想和她結婚?
What about her? You don't want to marry her?
完全不知道她想和我結婚!
I had no idea that she had any desire to marry me!
拜託 比爾! 你想讓她
Come on, Bill! Do you expect her to
跪下向你求婚嗎?
get down on bended knee and propose?
她也有自尊的
She has her pride!
所以 接下來想去哪呢?
So, what do you fancy?
附近的特倫絲太太那裏?
Mrs Terence's is nearby?
威爾斯那女孩一定有主了
The Welsh one will be taken by now and
其它人我看不上       福特太太那裏呢?
I don't much care for the others. Mrs Ford's?
性價比太差
Expensive for what you get.
這幾個看上去不錯啊      我們快活着呢
These have a cheerful air about them. Nice weather we're having.
你找不到比我更好的了 親愛的      我也是
You never had anyone like me, dear. Me neither!
口交 多少錢?
In the mouth. How much?
快點啊 先生      我今天沒有帶套
Go on, Sir. I don't have a sheath on me.
我上週去看過醫生 先生
I went to the doctors last week, Sir.
説我乾淨的像小貓
Says I'm as clean as a kitten.
可我...       我那裏美妙如絲綢 先生
Even so... I've got a fine, silky hole, sir.
如同絶美的海螺
A connoisseur's conch.
比爾 你還好嗎?
Bill, are you with us?
吃了它 拉克
Well, eat it, Rackers!
威廉?
William?
你在這裏幹什麼?      我來幫你處理信件
What are you doing in here? I'm attending to your correspondence.
你還好嗎 滿身是...
Are you all right? You're covered in...
你去哪了?
Where have you been?
噢 我怎麼會不知道?
Oh, I know, don't I?
我知道你去哪了
I know where you've been.
這與你無關!
That is none of your business!
給我瘸着回房間去
Just hobble off back to your room!
再也不需要你了
I have no further need for you.
走啊!
Go on!
「我究竟是誰?」
'Who am I?
「我叫蘇糖 你們眼中的失足婦女
'My name is Sugar. I am what you would call a fallen woman,
可我會告訴你這不是失足」
but I assure you I did not fall.
「我是被逼所至」
'I was pushed.
「卑劣的男人 永恆的亞當 我控訴你!」
'Vile man, eternal Adam, I indict you!'
請原諒      現在幾點了?
Please forgive me. What time is it?
快黎明了 蘇糖 對不起
Almost dawn. Sugar, I am so sorry.
我剛剛失控了
I wasn't myself before.
我喝醉了 癱倒在城裏
I collapsed in town, drunk.
丟盡了臉
A complete disgrace.
現在清醒了
I'm sober now.
再也不會發生這樣的事了
It will never happen again.
當然不會了 威廉      不 我下定決心了
Of course not, William. No, I am determined.
一切都會不同的
Things are going to be different.
你會發現的
You'll see.
明天希望你和索菲一起
I would like you and Sophie to join me tomorrow
來參觀我的香皂廠
on a visit of my soap factory.
不等你休養好再去嗎?
Wouldn't it be wiser to wait until after you're rested?
因為還有個人要見
There's someone else I am meeting there,
我不願意麻煩的人
someone I'm loath to inconvenience.
明白了
I see.
你當然明白
Of course you do.
雖然我沒掛在嘴邊 可你眞是個寳貝
I have not told you often enough what a treasure you are.
你該去睡會兒覺了
You should get some sleep now.
小心點 車伕
Take care, Cheesman.
我一直都是 蘇糖小姐
I always do, Miss Sugar.
你打扮的很美 索菲
You are very nicely turned out, Sophie.
看 索菲
Look, Sophie.
我們要見一個爸爸的生意夥伴
We're here to meet an associate of your father's.
不 怪我來的太早了
No, it is my fault for arriving early.
實在太想見你了
I've been looking forward to it so much, you see.
難得我的小小廠房
It's hard to believe my humble little factory
能讓你付諸如此熱情
could inspire such enthusiasm.
你不相信?
Do you doubt my word?
當然 你所看到的
Of course, what you see here is
不算是熬肥皂
not exactly soap manufacture, as such.
那些粗俗東西不太配的上一個香水製造商
That is a very dirty business and not the work of a perfumer.
小姐?       我沒事 索菲
Miss? I'm all right, Sophie.
這塊區域用來加工
This area is dedicated to the production of
拉克曼牌金銀花
Rackham's Honeysuckle.
據説它解除瘙癢有奇效
Relieves itching quite miraculously, I am told.
這個
Here.
威廉 這太有意思了
William, this is so amusing.
你眞的這樣想?
Do you really think so?
樓梯通往藍色車間
These stairs lead to the blue room,
用來生産
which houses the production of
拉克曼精油 我們的招牌香型
Rackham's Puressence, our signature scent.
這裏本來打算做汙水廠的
The factory was originally built to be a sewer works,
很好笑吧
which is ironic.
這是我們的新産品「青春永駐」
Ah, this is one of our new developments, Jeunesse Eternelle.
橙色來自於胡蘿蔔
The orange colour comes from carrots.
小姐 我想去尿尿
Miss, I need to go piddle.
拉克曼先生?
Mr Rackham?
這裏有...洗手間嗎?
Is there on the premises a room with... washing facilities?
嗯...有人會帶你去的
Er... someone will show you.
求你了 請你幫幫我
Please, please help me.
我去找別人
I'll get someone.
不! 只能你幫我
No! You have to help me.
求你了
Please.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我們必須得走
We must go.
走吧
Let's go.
離睡覺時間尚早
It's a bit early for bed.
我不管 小姐 我累了
I don't mind, miss, I'm tired.
我眞感激你 索菲
I'm very grateful to you, Sophie.
你救了我
You rescued me.
蘇糖小姐 求你別死
Please don't die.
我不會死
I won't die.
我保證
I promise.
沒事的 小東西
It's all right, little one.
什麼也不要擔心 只需相信我
Don't you worry about anything. You just trust me.
原諒我姍姍來遲 剛從你的鄰居那裏過來
Forgive the late hour. I was visiting a neighbour of yours.
什麼事?
What is it?
上次我來這裏時
There was something I could scarcely
無法忽視的事
fail to notice the last time I was in this house.
這次可能要同你説説了
I should perhaps have spoken to you about it at the time.
你讓我過來?
You sent for me?
是的
Yes.
不用坐 沒這個必要
Do not sit down, there's no need.
聽説你懷上了孩子
It has come to my notice that you are with child.
所以你不能留在這裏
It is therefore impossible that you remain
作我女兒的家庭教師了
as my daughter's governess.
你的工錢都在裏面
Your wages are enclosed.
請你在3月1日之前務必離開
Please be prepared to leave on 1st March.
這裏面有誤會吧
There has been a misunderstanding.
無需再多説了
Further discussion is out of the question.
你不用再來見我了
Do not attempt to come and see me again.
謝了
Thank you.
「親愛的威廉 原諒我這樣説 你弄錯了」
"Dear William, forgive me saying so, but you are mistaken.
「我之前飽受體內積水的困擾」
"I was briefly afflicted with a painful swelling
「現在已經沒有了 我的月事也正常」
"which has since passed and I now have my monthly courses,
「如果你不信 可以自己來檢査」
"as you can discover to your own satisfaction. "
「親愛的威廉 求你了」
"Dear William, please,
「每個小時等待你的回復 都是一種折磨」
"every hour that I wait for your reply is torture.
「記住我全心全意的協助你
"Remember that I am devoted to your assistance
為你分擔煩惱」
and you and sparing you inconvenience... "
打擾了 蘇糖小姐
Excuse me, Miss Sugar,
拉克曼先生讓索菲小姐下樓
Mr Rackham has asked if Miss Sophie might be brought down.
我們先整理一下
We shall just tidy ourselves up a bit.
蘇糖小姐 他讓我單獨帶索菲小姐下去
Miss Sugar, he asked me to bring Miss Sophie myself.
明白了
I see.
你可以在外面等一下嗎?      當然了 小姐
Could you wait outside a moment? Of course, Miss.
來 索菲 站起來
Come on, Sophie, stand up.
我想你父親會宣佈一些事情
I think your father has some news for you.
可能會告訴你一些事情
Most probably he is about to tell you something,
我希望你也能告訴他一些事
and I want you to tell him something in return.
你要告訴他你對我的感覺
I want you to tell him how you feel about me.
明白了嗎?
Do you understand?
一切都會好起來的
Then everything's going to be all right.
她們要把你送走
They're sending you away.
你告訴他了嗎?      我告訴他我愛你
But did you tell him? I told him that I love you.
他竟然做的出來?
How dare he do this?
他竟然這樣對我的孩子?!
How dare he do this to my child?!
唐思禮小姐
Miss Townsley.
你好 索菲
Hello, Sophie.
我來向你介紹一下唐思禮小姐
I would like to introduce you to Miss Townsley.
你好 唐思禮小姐
Hello, Miss Townsley.
你會説法語嗎 孩子?
Have you any French, child?
法語不是蘇糖小姐的技能
French wasn't one of Miss Sugar's accomplishments.
那鋼琴呢?
What about the piano?
也是 恐怕是蘇糖小姐不太稱職
Again, I'm afraid Miss Sugar came up rather short.
蘇糖小姐要立即離開
I think it best Miss Sugar leave immediately
免得帶給索菲更多困擾
to prevent further distress to Sophie.
鑑於你説她已經産生了很強的依戀感
If as you say she has formed a very strong attachment,
可能這樣最好
I think that might be preferable.
可你的家庭教師有地方去嗎?
But does your governess have somewhere to go?
當然 她隨時可以回家去找她媽
Oh, yes. She can always go home to her mother.
蘇糖小姐!
Miss Sugar!
今天我們可能要外出探險 索菲
I thought we might go for an adventure outside today, Sophie.
這裏太悶了      是的 小姐
It's so stuffy in here. Yes, miss.
別忘了你的圍脖      好的
Don't forget your muffler. Yes.
你的觀察鏡呢?
What about your spy glass?
天啊 小姐 我們帶上好多故事一起上路
Goodness, Miss, we are taking a lot of stories with us.
我們將進行一場偉大的冒險 索菲
We are going on a great expedition, Sophie,
誰知道會需要些什麼呢?
who knows what provisions we may need?
明天是美國嗎?
Is it America tomorrow?
明天是美國
America tomorrow.
拿着很重的包啊 小姐
Heavy bags you got there, Miss.
要遠行嗎?
Goin' far with them?
不得無禮 契斯曼
You're impertinent, Cheesman.
我回來的時候會告訴拉克曼先生?      你回來?
I shall speak to Mr Rackham about you on our return. Your return?
那是什麼時候?
That be soon then?
我們單獨談談
I shall speak to you in private.
索菲?  是的小姐  我一會就過來 好的 小姐
Sophie? Yes, Miss. I shall be back in a moment. Yes, Miss.
給你十鎊 契斯曼
Ten pounds, Cheesman.
大手筆呀     對你是一小筆橫財了
Aren't we grand! A small fortune for you.
拉克曼夫人遇難後
I wondered after Mrs Rackham met her doom
我以為你要取代她了
if you weren't hoping to take her place.
拿上錢 放我們走
Take the money, and let us be on our way.
我看到了她
I saw her.
從河裏拖上來
Dragged from the river.
一切都難以辨認了
There was nothing left to recognise.
除了她的頭髮
Except her hair.
長長的金髮
Those long blonde locks.
被汙水浸泡 纏繞着水草
Full of weed and dirty water.
你認為金錢如此美好 小姐
You see money's all well and good, Miss.
但我更想要點私人的東西
But what I'd like is something a little more personal.
我想試試他嚐過的
I want a taste of what he's had.
婊子
Bitch!
我們去哪裏 小姐?      美好的地方
Where are we going, Miss? Somewhere nice.
要我拿個包嗎 小姐?
Shall I carry a bag, Miss?
對你來説太重了 索菲!
They're too heavy for you, Sophie.
我們去坐公共馬車
Let's take a ride on the omnibus.
你跑上前去告訴他我們要坐
Run ahead so the conductor can see we want to get on.
我們現在要去哪裏 小姐?
Where are we going now, Miss?
非常有趣的地方
Somewhere very interesting.
我保證
I promise.
「讀者啊 你如此自大」
'How smug you are, reader,
「也許你的性別讓你
'if you are a member of that sex
以褲襠裏的那根軟骨為傲」
that boasts a scrag of gristle in your trousers.
「你想讓這本書吸引你 刺激你
'You fancy this book will amuse you, thrill you,
從無聊的恐怖中拯救你」
rescue you from the horror of boredom.
「而你讀完它
'And that, having consumed it,
還可以迴歸現實」
you will be left at liberty to resume your life as before.
「可這本書不同
'But this book is different.
這本書是把利刃 腦袋放機靈點
'This book is a knife. Keep your wits about you.
這是為你好」
'You will need them!'
有人嗎?
Hello?
開門!
Open the door!
我開不開門
Whether I open the door or not
要看你有多壞囉 你夠壞嗎?
depends on how bad a boy you've been. Have you been very bad?
我找卡特韋夫人
I want to speak to Mrs C-Castaway!
她死了很久了
She's long dead.
我找的是蘇糖
It's Sugar I'm after.
我必須要找到她
It is imperative that I f-find her.
付多少都行!     請你小聲一點 先生!
I'll pay whatever you ask! Please lower your voice, Sir!
首先 你要找的蘇糖已經放棄了風流生涯
Firstly, the girl you call Sugar has renounced the gay life.
第二  香皂和護膚膏上
Secondly, your soaps and ointments
印上你的形象毫無幫助
are not improved by having your image on them.
上帝 給個地方讓我們
Lord, grant us some places
見不到男人的臉吧
where we don't have to see a man's face.
最後 去找利克斯太太
And lastly, try Mrs Leek's.
四十畝地先生 榮幸啊!
Mr Forty Acres, we are honoured! You...
找我嗎 先生?      不
Lookin' for me, sir? No.
我在找蘇糖
I am looking for Sugar.
她偷走了我的女兒      偷走?
She has stolen my daughter! Stolen?
求你了 我什麼都沒了
Please, I have lost everything.
你知道 每十個在
Did you know, that of every ten persons
威爾斯和英格蘭淹死的人中
drowned in England and Wales,
六個都會是小孩?      她在你們這兒!
six will be children? You've got her!
嘿 七便士 先生!
Hey! Hey! Seven pence, sir!
注意腳下 先生 有些樓梯...
Watch your step, sir. Some of them stairs is...
小姐?
Miss?
睡覺前能到目的地嗎?
Will we get where we're going to go in time for bed?
我們要開始一段很長的旅程 索菲
We're going on a very long journey, Sophie.
當我們到那裏 我保證
But when we get there, I promise,
你會擁有世界上最溫暖
you will have the warmest, safest,
最安全 最舒服的床
nicest bed in the whole world.
明天是美國
America tomorrow.
紅玫瑰白玫瑰 全劇終 謝謝觀賞!